

Ramsay Shiells



Software Developer



Inverurie, Scotland

Profile

Software Developer with 5+ years of experience. Passionate about learning and exploring new technologies and I believe in producing clear and concise code in well structured applications. I also like cooking, gaming, playing the guitar, skiing and running.

Experience

Software Developer - Evolve Ltd

March 2014 - Present

- Designing, implementing and testing features in existing and new applications
- Maintaining and fixing bugs in historical applications
- Producing documentation
- Creating releases
- Supporting and mentoring Graduate Software Developers

Graduate Software Developer - Evolve Ltd September 2012 - March 2014

- Designing, implementing and testing features in existing applications
- Maintaining and fixing bugs in historical applications
- Customer Support and Operational Support

Ski Instructor & Attendant - Alford Ski Centre August 2004 - May 2015

- Instructing children and adults from beginner to expert level
- Maintenance of the dry ski slope and equipment
- Taking bookings and payments

Education

MSc Cloud Computing - Aberdeen University September 2011 - September 2012

"Creating, Publishing and Visualising Data for the Semantic Web" MSc Project in collaboration with IBM

BSc Hons Computing Science - Aberdeen University September 2008 - September 2011

"Making Linked Data Accessible" Honours Project in collaboration with Aberdeen City Council

Projects

Android App - Grampian Transport Museum January 2017 - March 2017

Application used to supplement exhibits with images and videos

Details

13-02-1988

www.ramsayshiells.info

ramsayshiells@me.com

Programming Languages

€ Java	
Js Javascript	
∃ HTML	
SQL	
∃ CSS	
RDF	
PHP	
© C#	

Frameworks

Alfresco	
Spring	
dōjō Dojo	
(Second Post of Second Post of Secon	
Android SDK	
∼ .NET	

Tools

Eclipse
Maven
Microsoft SQL Server
⋈ TFS
★ Atom
NySQL
G Github
aws